<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: genericinterface.xml,v 1.3 2011-08-04 04:33:34 cr Exp $ -->

<chapter id="genericinterface">
    <title>Generic Interface</title>
    <para>
        The OTRS Generic Interface consist on a multiple layer framework that let OTRS communicate
        with other systems via a web service. this communication could be in two different ways:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>OTRS as Provider: </emphasis> OTRS acts as a server listening request
                from the External System, processing the information, performing the requested
                action, and answering the request.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>OTRS as Requester: </emphasis> OTRS acts as a client collecting
                information, and sending the petition to the Remote System and waiting for the
                response.
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="genericinterface-layers.xml" />
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="genericinterface-communication-flow.xml" />

    <section id="genericinterface-webservices">
        <title>Web Services</title>
        <para>
            A Web Service is a communication method between two systems, in our case OTRS and a
            Remote System.
         </para>
         <para>
            The hart of the Web Service is it configuration, where is defined what actions does the
            web service can do internally (Operation), what can actions can OTRS request to the
            Remote System (Invokers), how data is converted from one system to the other (Mapping),
            And over which protocol the communication will be based on (Transport)
         </para>
         <para>
             Generic Interface is the framework that make possible to create Web Services for OTRS
             in an already defined way, using already made construction blocks that are independent
             from each other and interchangeable.
        </para>
    </section>
        <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="genericinterface-webservice-gui.xml" />
        <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="genericinterface-webservice-cli.xml" />
        <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="genericinterface-webservice-configuration.xml" />
</chapter>
