<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % local.common.attrib "xml:base  CDATA  #IMPLIED">
]>
<!-- $Id: GenericInterfaceDoc.xml,v 1.1 2011-08-15 17:46:09 cr Exp $ -->

<book lang="en">
    <bookinfo>
        <title>OTRS GI 1.0 - Developer Manual</title>
        <edition>First Beta</edition>
        <copyright>
            <year>2003-2011</year>
            <holder>OTRS AG</holder>
        </copyright>
        <date>2011-04-20</date>
        <legalnotice>
            <para>
René Bakker, Hauke Böttcher, Stefan Bedorf, Shawn Beasley, Jens Bothe, Udo Bretz, Martin Edenhofer, Martin Gruner,
Manuel Hecht, Christopher Kuhn, André Mindermann, Henning Oschwald, Thomas Raith, Stefan Rother, Burchard Steinbild
            </para>
            <para>
This work is copyrighted by OTRS AG.
            </para>
            <para>
You may copy it in whole or in part as long as the copies retain this
copyright statement.
            </para>
            <para>
UNIX is a registered trademark of X/Open Company Limited.
Linux is a registered trademark of Linus Torvalds.
            </para>
            <para>
MS-DOS, Windows, Windows 95, Windows 98, Windows NT, Windows 2000, Windows XP, Windows 2003
and Windows Vista are registered trademarks of Microsoft Corporation.
Other trademarks and registered trademarks are: SUSE and YaST of SUSE Linux GmbH,
Red Hat and Fedora are registered trademarks of Red Hat, Inc.
Mandrake is a registered trademark of MandrakeSoft, SA.
Debian is a registered trademark of Software in the Public Interest, Inc.
MySQL and the MySQL Logo are registered trademarks of MySQL AB.
            </para>
            <para>
All trade names are used without the guarantee for their free use and are
possibly registered trade marks.
            </para>
            <para>
OTRS AG essentially follows the notations of the manufacturers.
Other products mentioned in this manual may be trademarks of the respective
manufacturer.
            </para>
        </legalnotice>
    </bookinfo>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="content/get-started.xml" />
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="content/glossary.xml" />
</book>
