<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="webservice_gui">
    <title>Web service graphical interface</title>
    <para>
        The web service graphical interface is a great tool that allow us to construct complex web service
        configurations in a friendly and nice interface, with this interface is possible to create a new configuration,
        import and export configuration on YAML file format. Also it give you the chance to take a look on the history
        of the configuration, revert changes and export old configurations. One more feature included on this interface
        is a debugger reader, where you can review the log for the web service communications.
    </para>

    <section id="webservice_gui_overview">
        <para>
        The "Web Services" link on the Admin page allows you to manage your web service configurations.
        You can add or remove web service configurations.
        </para>

        <para>
            To create a new web service, press the button "Add web service", there you could provide the needed data.
        </para>

        <para>
            <screenshot>
            <screeninfo>Web Service Overview</screeninfo>
            <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web service - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/admin-webservice-overview.png"></graphic>
            </screenshot>
        </para>

        <para>
            <emphasis>Figure . Web services overview.</emphasis>
        </para>

    </section>

    <section id="webservice_gui_add">
        <para>
        Required data for the web service is just the name, the debug threshold value is set as default in "debug",
        it means that all the debug entries with a type over the debug threshold should be written on the log.
        For the provider and invoker sections only is possible to configure the network transport type.
        </para>

        <para>
            To create a new web service, press the button "Add web service", there you could provide the needed data.
        </para>

        <para>
            <screenshot>
            <screeninfo>Web service add</screeninfo>
            <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web service add - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/admin-webservice-add.png"></graphic>
            </screenshot>
        </para>

        <para>
            <emphasis>Figure . Web services overview.</emphasis>
        </para>

    </section>

    <section id="webservice_gui_change">
        <para>
        On this screen you have a complete set of functions to handled every part of a web service, on the left side
        in the action column you can found some buttons that allow you to perform all possible actions over a
        web service such, clone, export, import, history, delete and the access to the debugger log.
        </para>

        <para>
        For the "Configuration history", "Delete web service", and "Debugger" action there are separated screens to
        work with them.
        </para>




        <para>
        If you need to clone a web service just click on the "Clone web service" button, a new dialog showed
        introduce the name for the new web service (the system suggested one as default), and push the "Clone"
        button, or push the "Cancel" button if you want to stops the clone action.
        </para>

        <para>
            <screenshot>
            <screeninfo>Web service clone</screeninfo>
            <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web service clone - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/admin-webservice-clone.png"></graphic>
            </screenshot>
        </para>

        <para>
            <emphasis>Figure . Web service clone.</emphasis>
        </para>



        <para>
        The "Export web service" button give you the opportunity to dump the configuration of the current web service
        into a YAML file and download it. It file could be used for example to transfer a configuration from a test system
        to production system.
        </para>

        <para>
            <screenshot>
            <screeninfo>Web service export</screeninfo>
            <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web service export - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/admin-webservice-export.png"></graphic>
            </screenshot>
        </para>

        <para>
            <emphasis>Figure . Web services export.</emphasis>
        </para>



        <para>
        A valid web service configuration YAML file is required to use the import web service feature, if you have it, just
        click on the "Import web service" button, on the showed dialog select the YAML file with the configuration and press
        the "Import"" button or the "Cancel" button if you don't want to create the new web service.
        </para>

        <para>
            <screenshot>
            <screeninfo>Web service import</screeninfo>
            <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web service import - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/admin-webservice-import.png"></graphic>
            </screenshot>
        </para>

        <para>
            <emphasis>Figure . Web services import.</emphasis>
        </para>



        <para>
        Some times it's necessary the complete content for a web service configuration, on this cases we can press the
        "Delete web service" button and a new dialog will ask you if you really want to delete the web service, press
        the "Delete" button to confirm the action or just cancel it pressing the "Cancel" button.
        </para>

        <para>
            <screenshot>
            <screeninfo>Web service delete</screeninfo>
            <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web service delete - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/admin-webservice-delete.png"></graphic>
            </screenshot>
        </para>

        <para>
            <emphasis>Figure . Web service delete.</emphasis>
        </para>




        <para>
        Returning to the web service change screen, now we are going to review the right side of it, where we have the possibility to modify
        all the general data for a web service such, name, description, remote system, etc... Also there are two more section that
        allow us to modify parameters for use OTRS as a provider and for use OTRS as a requester.
        </para>

        <para>
        On the "OTRS as provider" section you have the possibility to change the setting for the network transport that will be used
        to interact with OTRS when it offers webservices, it's just necessary to push the 'Configure' button to be redirected to a new
        screen where you could set all necessary parameters.
        Also exists the option to add and list the availables operations for the web service, for do it, select the operation to add
        on the "Add operation" select box at the end of the dialog
        </para>

        <para>
        Next down you can see the "OTRS as requester" section you have the same possibility to change the setting for the network
        as in the last section.
        For this section you can add and list invokers for the web service, for do it, select the operation to add
        on the "Add operation" select box at the end of the dialog
        </para>

        <para>
        At the end if you want to save your changes and review them, please push the "Save" button or press the "Save and finish"
        button if you want to save and back to the webservice overview.
        </para>

        <para>
            <screenshot>
            <screeninfo>Web service change</screeninfo>
            <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web service change - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/admin-webservice-change.png"></graphic>
            </screenshot>
        </para>

        <para>
            <emphasis>Figure . Web services change.</emphasis>
        </para>

    </section>

</section>
